In a place that defied belief their only hope was each other.
The Magdalene Sisters is a drama, history film directed by Peter Mullan.
Three young Irish women struggle to maintain their spirits while they endure
dehumanizing abuse as inmates of a Magdalene Sisters Asylum.
Margaret, played by Anne-Marie Duff.
Bernadette, played by Nora-Jane Noone.
Rose, played by Dorothy Duffy.
Sister Bridget, played by Geraldine McEwan.
Crispina, played by Eileen Walsh.
Una, played by Mary Murray.
The Magdalene Sisters is a 2002 drama film written and directed by Peter Mullan, about three teenage girls who were sent to Magdalene
asylums (also known as Magdalene laundries), homes for women who were labelled as "fallen" by their families or society.
The homes were maintained by individual religious
orders, usually by the Catholic Church.
Peter Mullan has remarked that the film was initially made because victims of Magdalene asylums had received no
closure in the form of recognition, compensation or apology, and many remained lifelong devout Catholics.
Former Magdalene inmate Mary-Jo McDonagh told Mullan that the reality of the
Magdalene asylums was much worse than depicted in the film.
Some people have questioned some of the depictions
of these institutions in the film.
Though set in Ireland, the film was shot entirely on location
in Dumfries and Galloway, South-West Scotland.
The film was distributed by Miramax, run at the time by Harvey Weinstein.
The convent used for the film location was badly damaged by fire on 9 August
2022; it had been St Benedict's Convent in West Dumfries.
The film explores themes of nun, girls' boarding school,
based on true story, sin, psychological abuse.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.